<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Plot on Nishadh KA</title>
    <link>/tags/plot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Plot on Nishadh KA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/plot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Print map shape file python</title>
      <link>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-12/print_map_shape_file_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-12/print_map_shape_file_python/</guid>
      <description>####Create and print map using pandas in python from SHAPE file#####
 Based on this note to print map from shape file, a sort of scripting map creation and printing without using qgis kind GUI. The above note uses fiona lib. Intsallation of fiona is super easy with anaconda. Command conda install fiona does all the jobs of installing with all its depndancy starting from gdal. Native installtion of gdal and linkingit with python libs are super hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plot NETCDF</title>
      <link>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-10/plot_netcdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-10/plot_netcdf/</guid>
      <description>###Plot NETCDF and create xlsx file for pyWRFChemEmiss####
 The 2010 anthropogenic emission file of Asian region is available in NetCDF format. To use it with WRF CHEM, PREPCHEMSRC is limited use mainly because the emission source has to specify, and its conversion factor might not be correct. Complexity/understandability is case for similar emission converter program such as Air Emissions Processor program and SMOKE. In this regard pyWRFChemEmiss give a more modular and easy interface to convert emission file to be used with wrf chem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WRFCHEM domain view python</title>
      <link>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-09/wrfchem_domain_view_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-09/wrfchem_domain_view_python/</guid>
      <description>####WRF_CHEM domain view by python script####
 WRF CHEM domain in nested has to be visualized to correct the nesting and for domain size adjustment. There are few tools available to do that such as dwiz of wrf ems and plotgrid.ncl. There is an alternative with python based on this, it is a wrf script tools for visualizing and nesting based simulation. Set of scripts available has a function to visualize the namelist.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>