<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web Application on Nishadh KA</title>
    <link>/tags/web-application/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web Application on Nishadh KA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/web-application/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Plot Aerocet sample D3JS</title>
      <link>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-11/plot_aerocet_sample_d3js/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-11/plot_aerocet_sample_d3js/</guid>
      <description>####Plot aerocet data with D3 JS scrip####
 Based on this and its source code. One index.html file combines the code for the meteor web application. Web map marker codes are in the file JS drawMap.js. The index.html was edited to remove the CHART in line 14 to 19 contains  &amp;lt;div id=&amp;quot;year-chart&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;chart display&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Year of Impact&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div id=&amp;quot;mass-chart&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;chart display&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Mass (g)&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;   IN drawMap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Github pages, HTML, css and js</title>
      <link>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-07/gh-pages-html-css-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-07/gh-pages-html-css-js/</guid>
      <description> The files HTML, css and js, is enough for creating a web site. In GitHub this is detrimental in any gh-pages intended to create. There are several templates available to render web pages A simple markdown template used is, . https://github.com/aplib/markdown-site-template Final usage of this web site was selected based on its demonstration  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node js with AIRwind and Earthwind applications</title>
      <link>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-05/node-js-withairwindandearthwind/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-05/node-js-withairwindandearthwind/</guid>
      <description>To address objective2 of web processing service for real-time air pollution model, the implementation with node.jsearth or airis planned. These are the perfect match for this objective in showing the grandioseness of air circulation and how air pollution effect this grandioseness in real time animation of wind As a node.js web application, it has to installed as specified in the project&amp;rsquo;s readme. For node installation followed this wonderful tutorial, it involves and checking with node -v and npm -v</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QualitySCHU to cbe air</title>
      <link>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-05/qualityschu-to-cbe-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-05/qualityschu-to-cbe-air/</guid>
      <description>Qualityschu(qs) is a web application coupled with istsos sensor web; it&amp;rsquo;s elegant, simple HTML with javascript design makes it easy to work with and to be educative. It is base code to build particulate matter air quality monitors web application in Coimbatore named cbeair web application. The app&amp;rsquo;s main difference with the source(qs) would be its ability to work with GitHub pages It is an HTML file with map and menu javascript files, main functions it provides is map view, table, chart view, and download functions coupled with istSOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SMS management web application</title>
      <link>/working-notes/2013/wn_2013-11/sms-management-web-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-notes/2013/wn_2013-11/sms-management-web-application/</guid>
      <description>Use
http://kalkun.sourceforge.net/</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>