<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latex on Nishadh KA</title>
    <link>/tags/latex/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Latex on Nishadh KA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/latex/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel Pandas LATEX PDF</title>
      <link>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-10/excel_pandas_latex_pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-10/excel_pandas_latex_pdf/</guid>
      <description>###CSV data into pandas and LATEX then into PDF and then print!###
 To import csv file with date into pandas data frame. Pandas can parse the date column, but it won&amp;rsquo;t be correct. The date column formate has top be mentioned and parsed for this, like below based on [this], then this can be imported into pandas data frame indicating the date parser.  dateparse = lambda x: pd.datetime.strptime(x, &amp;lsquo;%d/%m/%y&amp;rsquo;) pro=pd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latex beamer based pdf presentation</title>
      <link>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-07/latex-beamer-based-pdf-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-07/latex-beamer-based-pdf-presentation/</guid>
      <description> For creating a presentation with many images in it, better to use latex based presentation It is easier than ppt with tight control on formatting and content referencing The presentation is based on this note and chosen Berlin theme within beamer&amp;rsquo;s n number of various themes. The main problem faced is with BibTeX based referencing, and could not be solved and used normal superscript referencing. Another problem faced was box and its colour choosing, it was solved following this excellent tutorial  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert Latex into HTML</title>
      <link>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-06/latex-into-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-06/latex-into-html/</guid>
      <description> For a workflow with latex and peer editing, latex in PDF has to converted into some editable formate can be used in text editor/word processor Based on this, latex tex files can be directly converted into HTML without going for pdf. Have to use this command htlatex mydocument.tex, but asks to install the program sudo apt-get install tex4ht, so install tex4ht Then execute the command of htlatex mydocument.tex and it produced HTML with css and other required files, this can be open in Libre text editor to make peers to edit or correct the content  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert pandas dataframe into a PDF file using Latex</title>
      <link>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-05/pandas-dataframe-into-latex-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-05/pandas-dataframe-into-latex-pdf/</guid>
      <description>Huge data frames which go for multiple A4 pages landscape is difficult to make in excel The alternative uses python pandas and convert the pandas&amp;rsquo; data frame into pdf through latex or HTML, latex is promising for just printing Basically from ([1])(http://stackoverflow.com/questions/14380371/export-a-latex-table-from-pandas-dataframe) for convert data frame into tex and this for converting Tex into landscape pdf document The python script to make table text is as follows, It is mostly from third answer [1], and bold column heading write python trick from</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>