<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beagle Bone Black board on Nishadh KA</title>
    <link>/tags/beagle-bone-black-board/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beagle Bone Black board on Nishadh KA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/beagle-bone-black-board/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>WRF CHEM compilingInARM BeagleBoneBlack</title>
      <link>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-08/wrf_chem_compilinginarm_beagleboneblack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-08/wrf_chem_compilinginarm_beagleboneblack/</guid>
      <description>###WRF CHEM compiling in ARM architecture, Beagle Bone Black###
This is based on http://www2.mmm.ucar.edu/wrf/OnLineTutorial/index.php ####compiler test#### went successful, except in test4 using 64 bit ###libraries### ####Netcdf compiling#### 1. Environment has to be properly setup, following was correct for ARM arch, clarified based on this
 export DIR=/media/card/wrf/lib export CC=gcc export CXX=g++ export FC=gfortran export FCFLAGS=-g export F77=gfortran export FFLAGS=-g export CXXFLAGS=-g   Faced error in make after configure command of .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing mysql database in Beagle Bone Black</title>
      <link>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-05/mysql-bbb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-05/mysql-bbb/</guid>
      <description>Based on 1 and 2
apt-get install mysql-server apt-get install phpmyadmin  The phpmyadmin not showing up, so working with mysql command line followed this to get into mysql shell /usr/bin/mysql -u root -p
 To create a new database followed this by create database gammu in mysql shell
 To execute gammu mysql.sql file to create tables for gammu back end, used this mysql -u root -p’passwd’ and then run the command gammu &amp;lt; /home/debian/gammu-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mount SDcard in Beagle Bone Black</title>
      <link>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-05/mount-sdcard-with-bbb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-05/mount-sdcard-with-bbb/</guid>
      <description>Mounting SD card is not so easy with BBB, it is due to the problem of MySQL error, saying sock file is missing and while starting saying /var folder is full By checking df -h shows it is true. So only way to increase the partition in sd card, but regular sd card with partition cannot mount with BBB, due to some kernel inclination There is a workaround, based on [this] under title code listing 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compile Gammu in Beagle Bone Black</title>
      <link>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-05/gammu-compile-bbb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-05/gammu-compile-bbb/</guid>
      <description>Gammu was compiled in BBB following this The dependencies were installed using this command
apt-get install cmake python-dev pkg-config libmysqlclient-dev libpq-dev \ libcurl4-gnutls-dev libusb-1.0-0-dev libdbi0-dev libbluetooth-dev \ libgudev-1.0-dev libglib2.0-dev unixodbc-dev  The command ./configure gives error of CMake Error: CMake was unable to find a build program corresponding to &amp;quot;Unix Makefiles&amp;quot;.
 Based on this installed make by apt-get install make after this the error goes away
 Executed this command cmake .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sending SMS with Beagle bone black</title>
      <link>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-03/sending_sms_with_beagle_bone_black/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-03/sending_sms_with_beagle_bone_black/</guid>
      <description>BBB is setup with Angstrom Linux, first connected to Ubuntu lap using USB wire from BBB, then a USB was connected to the powered USB hub, in which a serial USB connector and a Huwaei e 173 data (This tested for Huwaei E303F, it worked) card were connected. ssh&amp;rsquo;s into it using ssh 192.168.7.2 -l root and password blank (an enter) lsusb shows Huwaei with modem and serial usb. Need to make usb_modeswitch for Huwaei GSM to sent SMS, so usb_modeswitch has to be installed in the Angstrom, downloaded ipk file (deb in angstrom) from http://feeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to BRICK Beagle Bone Black</title>
      <link>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-01/how-to-brick-beagle-bone-black/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-notes/2014/wn_2014-01/how-to-brick-beagle-bone-black/</guid>
      <description>Doing a apt-get update and upgrade make BBB&amp;rsquo;s internal hard disk to crash, to solve this is to make a recovery SD card and rewrite the hard disk
 After a long searching for making the SD card finally followed this http://www.armhf.com/index.php/getting-started-with-ubuntu-img-file/ Installed the xz in ubuntu laptop apt-get install xz-utils then viewed the attached sd card device name by ls /dev/sd* given it as sdb so to run the xz, followed this http://downloads.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>